Hi everybody, I'm John Kiriakou and
welcome to our first Q&A here at the
briefing room. I want to thank everyone
who submitted questions for this our
first Q&A episode. We've been looking
forward to this for a long time. We'll
have another one soon. We'll try to do
them regularly, so please continue to
send the questions and if possible,
please try to keep them under 100 words.
We've received hundreds of questions.
We're going to We're going to try to
tackle the first 20 or 20 five,
something like that. Um so thanks.
Thanks for submitting. Also, there we
We've gotten a lot where people are
asking the same questions, so we've just
lumped them together. So I'm going to
start with Jack. Jack says, "How is the
issue of the pardon going? I've been
watching you since before the TikTok
success and I love the show." Thank you,
Jack.
How's the pardon going? It's going.
I have, without get going too deep into
the details, I have enlisted the help
of every Republican in Washington who
has the ear of the president. And I was
speaking to a congressman a few days ago
who has very kindly volunteered to help
me only out of the goodness of his own
heart. He's not asking anything of me.
And he said to me, when I gave him
everything that I had, he said to me,
"My God, if you've got all this support
and you're not pardoned yet,
you're probably not getting pardoned."
And I said, "Yeah, that's kind of what I
assumed." And he said, "Let me
investigate it a little bit." And so he
investigated and he got back to me a
couple of days ago and he said the CIA
absolutely, positively does not want you
to get pardoned.
So he said, "It's still possible,
but we're going to have to go
head-to-head with the CIA on this." So,
you know, it's a process. President
Trump is going to be president a little
bit more than uh, two year two more
years, two and a half years he'll be
president. And so, I don't feel any
particular rush. I'm getting all my
ducks in order and I'm hoping for the
best.
Matthew says, "If back in the day you
did agree with the CIA torture program,
do you think you'd still be with them
today? And how different do you think
your life would have been?" Yeah, good
question. My ex-wife and I have actually
talked about this. She was also a senior
CIA officer. She said to me one time,
"If you had never objected to torture,
where do you think we would be right
now?"
And half jokingly I said, "Well, we
would both be in the senior intelligence
service.
I would be recovering from my first
heart attack and you would be trying to
lose that pesky 40 lb.
And then we had a laugh.
Uh, the truth is I would be retired by
now. I was eligible to retire, get this,
the day that I turned 56 because I had 5
years overseas, uh, service in dangerous
posts.
Um, and, uh,
and I had, uh, the the 25 years in. So,
I would probably
have retired on a Friday and returned on
Monday in exactly the same job but with
a green contractor's badge instead of a
blue staff badge. I probably would be
making tons of money which they mostly
do as contractors. Um, but I couldn't
have slept with myself, lived with
myself. I I couldn't have looked my
children in the eye.
Um, you know what? No regrets. Life is
what we make of it and, uh, knock on
wood, I like to think that I've made
something out of it.
JB,
"How can someone identify a diplomat or
spy? I've heard from a few friends in
diplomacy that the economic affairs, I'm
sorry, the economic officer or the
political attaché sticks out like a sore
thumb. Also, what are the obvious cover
positions? And whether there are any
on-the-nose positions that should raise
eyebrows with the general population.
Very good question, very difficult to
answer. So,
economic officer, political officer,
political attaché, of course those are
cover positions.
Or they're not.
Meaning, the State Department has to do
its business of diplomacy every day. And
so, there are State Department officers
literally in every country in the world
in which the United States has an
embassy who are political attachés or
economic officers or whatever. So, the
answer to your question is
every position is a cover position.
That's what makes it cover.
You can be, you know, the agricultural
attaché, the commercial officer, you can
be
anything inside or outside an embassy.
Amaryllis Fox Kennedy, who until
recently was the Deputy National
Security Advisor and is the
daughter-in-law of
Bobby Kennedy Jr., she was a deep cover
officer, and her cover was that she was
uh
a fine art consultant.
I met a deep cover officer once who was
a uh
wildlife photographer.
You just never know. The answer is
anything and everything.
So, everything should raise an eyebrow
and nothing should raise an eyebrow.
That's kind of the bottom line of cover.
Blake, what kind of cars do spies use
when working in the field? I like this
question.
Did you ever have a favorite type,
brand, or model of vehicle? And what
were the defining characteristics of a
vehicle that made it good for
operational use? It depends on what
country you're in.
So,
in most of the countries where I served
operationally,
and they were almost exclusively in the
Middle East,
my car was whatever the rental car
company gave me.
Seriously.
Most of the time it was a Toyota of some
sort, Corolla, Camry, whatever, no big
deal. Couple of the times it was a
Volkswagen. I think I had a Nissan one
time. When I was in Athens though, it
was different.
I needed something that was fully
armored with level four armor. And so we
had to special order a BMW 540. I need I
needed it.
Big engine.
Big enough to carry all that armor.
Um I did not like that BMW at all.
It was
not
uh retrofitted. It was factory fitted,
both the armor and the big engine. And
still it it was just not meant to be.
So it broke down constantly. It
protected me, you know, in case somebody
wanted to try to assassinate me while
I'm sitting in traffic, which thank god
didn't happen. But um
But yeah, for for most of us
doing counterterrorism, it was either
armored BMWs or armored Jeeps. Most of
the guys had armored Jeeps.
Um the Jeeps break down all the time,
too. So you kind of just take what you
get.
Paul, from your time inside the CIA as
someone who became a whistleblower, what
psychological or institutional forces
lead good people to stay silent? Wow,
this is a good question.
When they see wrongdoing. Looking back,
do you view those who stayed quiet as
complicit or simply trapped? And should
the public judge them for it? Wow,
buddy. This is a very deep question.
Um
Maybe I'm maybe I'm the forgiving sort.
But
I don't blame most of my colleagues.
Most of them
most of them were not
Uh most of them very quietly, privately
opposed the torture program.
But,
you know,
they had pensions and families and
mortgages and kids and you can't rock
the boat.
I'm one of those guys who just couldn't
keep silent. Most people can keep
silent. And so, most of my former
colleagues just did not want
to rock the boat. Certainly, in the
Counterterrorism Center Center, there
were
there were many who were complicit. And
not just complicit, they they've written
books about how great torture was and
what a great idea it was and how many
lives it saved. It's all of
course.
But, um
but a lot of them have tried to uh to
justify their actions. I I went to the
Spy Museum 2 weeks ago and I gave a
family a tour of the Spy Museum. And
there was a little room just dedicated
to the torture program.
And they have this loop of videos going
and the only people that they're looping
are the torturers.
And I'm never mentioned in that in that
video.
Only the pro-torture people
uh are giving their side of the story.
It's it's sickening.
Billy,
are you a religious guy? You've been
around the world and met people of many
religions. Have you studied any
religions? I am a religious guy. I'm a
practicing Greek Orthodox. I keep a
little card of Saint Nectarios of Aegina
next to me just because I identify with
him. He's somebody who was wronged and
lied about and and
forgave the people who had wronged him,
but for the rest of his life tried to
rehabilitate his reputation. So, I kind
of identify with him. I studied Islam
extensively and my minor in uh in my
bachelor's program was in Islamic
theology, something that I'm actually
quite proud of. I studied mostly Shiism,
which I find fascinating.
Um
but yeah, I have studied religions.
Uh in fact, it wasn't just Shiism. I
studied under under Seyyed Hossein Nasr,
who's the
the father of Vali Nasr, and probably
the most important Shia Muslim scholar
in the world. He's 98 years old now.
Um and believe it or not, he's still
teaching. It's crazy. But um but I also
studied uh Judaism under Dr. Paul Jones
at at George Washington University. You
know, I've got my own faith. I'm one of
those people who sort of keeps it to
myself. Um if people want to believe,
go for it. If they don't want to
believe,
I'm perfectly fine with that, too. None
of my business.
But for me, yeah, it's kind of a it's
kind of an important part of my life.
Uh Ahmed, what is your opinion on Flock
cameras? Are Snowden's predictions
coming true? Flock cam What a Flock
camera is is it's like a
let's say like a license plate reader.
Where sometimes they'll be mounted on
the back of police cars, sometimes
they'll be mounted on poles that look
like telephone poles. I'll tell you
there's one that stops me all the
freaking time, and it's a block from the
White House at 15th and Constitution
Avenue. I can't tell you how many times
I've gotten pulled over right smack
behind the White House at 16th and
Constitution.
Uh because I once reported my license
plate stolen, not both of them, just one
of them, and
every time I pull over, I'm like, you
guys, when are you guys going to get
your act together?
That that's a different story. Anyway,
uh I think Flock cameras are
a direct assault on our civil liberties.
Seriously, I think they're far more
dangerous than people realize because
they're blanket surveillance, constant
surveillance.
The the authorities know where we are at
any given time of the day.
I mean, maybe we're going to the dry
cleaners or going to the grocery stores
or going to a clandestine meeting.
You never know.
But they're on us.
And are Snowden's predictions come true?
They've already come true. Yes.
Yes, and it's dangerous because nobody
on Capitol Hill cares.
It's just not important enough.
William, if the department you worked
for years ago asked you to come back one
last time for a mission they needed help
with and needed someone with your level
of knowledge and experience, would you
ever consider going doing it one last
time if they apologized about
everything, paid you a lot of money, and
just to experience how they run that
department now compared to when you and
your team were working in it back then?
I will admit to you I would consider it.
I'm going to add something too that I
haven't said publicly.
I met with a cabinet member
about 6 months ago about the pardon.
And he asked me to write something very
specific. So, I I did
all the research. I took this very
seriously. I wrote it. I submitted it.
And he said to me that the person the
person that I was trying to impress
appreciated
the paper.
And I said I was very happy to write the
paper for him, but I'm going to make a
request.
I said if John Ratcliffe were to resign
as the director of the CIA,
even if it's on the last day
of the Trump presidency,
I want to be the CIA director.
I want to be the one to walk in that
hallway and say, "Guess who's back?"
Even if it's for one single day.
But I'm not bitter.
Anyway, Zach,
do you think there will be some sort of
a revolution in the US in the next 100
years?
Or is that just something groups in each
generation say? It seems the US is
having toward a point of no return
economically, politically, socially,
technologically, etc.
I don't know how long it will take, but
I believe something is coming for the
oligarchs, politicians, inevitably.
People can't take corruption and greed
forever. You know what, Zach? I have to
agree with you.
First of all, you're right that every
generation says, "Oh, these events are
unprecedented."
Actually, these events are
unprecedented. We've never had
trillionaires.
You know, you've heard the phrase eat
the rich, which is something that, you
know, revolutionaries say.
But when
when five men
when five white men
have as much wealth
as the bottom, whatever it is, 80% of
the world's population,
there's a problem with distribution of
wealth.
Nobody is worth a trillion dollars. I
don't care what you do.
You're not worth a trillion dollars.
And so, yeah, I think something's
coming. And it's not just for that. Um
the defense budget is untenable.
Uh it's a trillion dollars. The
administration's asking for 1.5 trillion
dollars. We're practically bankrupt as a
country.
And so, what are you going to do? You're
going to cut social security? You're
going to cut Medicare, Medicaid? You're
going to cut, you know, aid to hungry
children? You're going to cut education?
You're going to cut highway funds? For
what?
To make more F-35s and and missiles?
The whole situation's untenable. Um I'm
glad you didn't say the next 10 years.
Uh I don't think we're going to see
anything like that in the next 10 years.
In the next 100 years, yeah, something's
coming. There's going to have to be a
major societal change because this
situation, this this
thing that we've created,
it's just not tenable over the long
term.
Aiden, what's your favorite bird in the
Angry Birds game? You know, actually
people ask me this a lot.
And uh I don't have a single friendly
bird.
Um first of all, I like the black bird
very much cuz he explodes. I like the
inflating bird very much because he
inflates and destroys everything. But
some of these new birds, like that sucks
everything up and then spits it out,
love him. The newest one, the white one
that spins around and destroys
everything, love him. I will say I don't
like Stella, the uh the pink bird.
Stella's very weak. I don't like the
blue bird very much because the blue
bird only can destroy glass.
And so those are my two least favorite
birds. And even the small red bird that
only can knock things over, uh
I don't know. I could take her or leave
her.
But I still love the game.
I just finished playing it 15 minutes
ago.
Jordan, what is MK Ultra and how has it
been used in the past? Is it still being
done today?
So a lot has been written about MK
Ultra. MK Ultra was a secret, actually
it was a top secret CIA program that was
begun in 1952 and ended unceremoniously
in 1975 when it was exposed to the
Church Committee, which later became the
Senate Select Committee on Intelligence.
MK Ultra did things like um studied
ESP, astral projection, mind reading, uh
crazy stuff. The The CIA was
experimenting with LSD. They were dosing
their own employees until they began
committing suicide.
Then they began dosing innocent
Americans on the street. MK Ultra had
several sub um operations, like MK
Chickwit is another one.
um where
oh the CIA had recruited prostitutes in
San Francisco to pick up johns,
customers, and dose them with LSD just
to see if they would confess their
deepest darkest secrets. Um MK Ultra
included an operation where a germ was
released into the atmosphere in San
Francisco, and 11 people came down with
a very rare upper respiratory infection.
Um
all of it was illegal.
Al- Almost all of it was against
American citizens.
You hear a lot that from
uh especially on the internet about MK
Ultra taking place now.
No, it's not taking place now. There are
a lot of people who think that the CIA
is beaming waves at their heads, and the
CIA is is stealing their dreams, and is
communicating with them through chips in
their heads. That's not MK Ultra, that's
mental illness.
And it's actually quite common.
But MK Ultra was bad, bad, bad, no
matter how you look at it.
It ran for 23 years. It ended. Certainly
there are elements of MK Ultra that were
renamed, that were approved by the
congressional oversight committees, and
are probably still taking place. But MK
Ultra, the original MK Ultra with all
the LSD experiments and, you know, mind
reading and nah.
All done.
Shay, what are sleeper agents, and do
you think we have them in the US today
right now? If so, where from? Absolutely
yes, we do.
Uh and they're almost exclusively from
Russia and China. So, a sleeper agent is
someone who is trained as an
intelligence officer by a foreign
intelligence service, and then sent to
the United States and told
to just
live as an American, pretend to be an
American, get a job, and just wait until
we contact you. But that person may wait
for 20, 25, 30 years before being
uh contacted.
Um
less than 2 years ago
a woman in my neighborhood was arrested.
She was an elementary school teacher in
the Arlington County, Virginia public
school system and here she was a Russian
sleeper agent waiting to be activated.
So, yeah, they're out there. Um there
was an arrest like
a year ago, 2 years ago, here in I'm in
New York City right now. Uh here in New
York, it was a group of Chinese working
for the Chinese uh national security uh
service um just going around New York
threatening Chinese and telling them to
keep their mouths shut or something
terrible was going to happen to them.
So, yeah, they're out there.
Chase
Regarding 2028 presidential candidates,
who do you think we will see running?
And who do you think represent private
agendas versus those who prioritize
genuine transparency? Wow, buddy. There
are only two who prioritize
genuine
honest-to-god transparency. For the
Republicans, it is Thomas Massie.
For the Democrats, it is Ro Khanna.
Um if you've ever heard of the app
Kalshi,
it's one of these predictive apps
and right now they list 66 people, 44
Democrats and 22 Republicans, that they
consider to be potential presidential
candidates.
Too many to name here.
Um
the real race is going to be
you know, among the Democrats, of
course, the frontrunner is uh Gavin
Newsom, the governor of California.
We're all going to also going to see
J.B. Pritzker, the governor of Illinois,
probably Rahm Emanuel, the former uh
mayor of Chicago, um you know, and a
handful of other people.
Uh
Pete Buttigieg, et cetera, et cetera.
For the Republicans,
the there are two heavyweights. It's
J.D. Vance, the vice president, and
Secretary of State Marco Rubio.
Everybody seems to think that
J.D. Vance is going to be the nominee. I
don't think that's the case. I think
it's going to be Rubio. Rubio is already
tested. He's run for president. He's
been a senator. Now he's been a cabinet
member. He's been a He's been an
attorney and a congressman. J.D. Vance
is is practically a kid. The guy, what,
just turned 40.
And so, he could run for president for
the next 30 to 35 years. I think that
he's got a good shot at being president
someday. I don't think he's got a shot
at being president in 2028. But I don't
think anybody besides Thomas Massie and
Ro Khanna really believe in
transparency.
Ahmed, have you have you ever
had a failed operation? If so, what
happened?
>> [laughter]
>> Yes, one time.
>> Ah, yeah, it was not my fault.
So,
God, I got to be careful here. So,
there was a terrorist suspect.
And
and I heard from a source that
the guy really needed money. He was
having some serious problems. His
daughter was sick. He couldn't afford
medical care. And um so, I I called him
out of the blue.
And I said my name was, you know, Joe
Blow.
The guy was a journalist. That was his
kind of his cover. He was a terrorist,
but he he was a journalist for a leftist
newspaper.
So, I called him and I said I was the I
was the editor of this uh new magazine.
And um you know, because of his
reputation in the the leftist community,
we we wanted to offer him a column.
And we could pay him, you know, a a
dollars a month or two thousand a month,
whatever it happened to be. I don't
remember anymore.
Um and would he like to meet for a
coffee and we could talk about the
magazine.
Oh my god, yes. He would love to meet
for the coffee. Okay, I was so excited.
I'm going to get in front of a bonafide
terrorist. I run into the station
chief's office and I tell him. And he
says, "Okay, okay." He's so excited. He
goes, "Okay, I'm going to do the pitch."
I'm like, "What? I've been working on
this guy for two years." "I'm going to
do the pitch. I'm going to do the
pitch."
"What's your cover?" And I told him what
my cover was. He says, "Okay, I'm going
to be I'm going to be the magazine's
publisher. You be the editor, I'll be
the publisher."
I'm like, "Okay."
So, I called the guy back
and um
I offered up two different restaurants
to meet in and
he was very smart. He said, "No,
I don't want to meet in those
restaurants. I want to meet at this
outdoor cafe." Now, this outdoor cafe
was surrounded on four sides by really
high hedges. So, even though it was the
in the center of town, you couldn't see
who was sitting at the cafe because of
the hedges. It was very smart from a
cover perspective.
And so,
we go there to meet the guy. We go half
an hour early and we order some coffees
and every other table
every other table in the place was CIA
people. All doing security cuz this is
what we call a high threat meeting.
And so,
I see the guy in the distance. I I'm
talking to my boss, drinking my coffee
and I said, "Here he comes. He's
directly behind you."
And the guy arrives. I said, "Hello, Mr.
So-and-so. I'm Joe Blow. I spoke to you
on the
on the phone. This is my publisher, Mr.
Wilson."
"Oh, hello. How are you?" My boss grabs
his hand to shake his hand and then
won't let it go
and then says, "We know who you are,
mother
We know who you are. We're going to
break you." And I'm like, "What are you
What are you doing?"
The soft touch is always the way to go.
He threatened the guy. The guy gets
really scared, and then he starts
screaming, "Police! Police!"
I bolt this way, the boss bolts that
way, all the security guys are running
these other directions.
The guy's screaming for the police.
We reconnoitered back at the embassy.
And he goes, my boss, he says,
"I think that succeeded." And I said,
"Succeeded?
You scared the out of him.
And he called the police."
And he says, "Yeah, but we we drove him
underground. He's not going to be doing
any operations." I said, "I wanted to
recruit him, not drive him underground."
Next thing you know,
the ambassador calls us in.
"Did you just approach this journalist?"
We're like,
"Yes."
"How do you know?"
And the ambassador says, "Because the
deputy prime minister just called me to
lodge a complaint."
So, we screwed that up. And
and then
he actually volunteered
to another intelligence service, and
they came to us and said, "Actually, I
was visiting their capital." And they
said, "Did you approach so-and-so?"
I said, "How could you possibly know
that?"
And he said, uh, this other intelligence
officer, he said to me, "He volunteered
to us."
And when we were polygraphing him,
we said, "Have you ever been approached
by another intelligence officer?" And
his answer was, "I was approached by two
caricatures of CIA men."
It was a disaster from the word go.
Gavin,
"Hey John, are you a government plant?
It seems like maybe the CIA offered to
let you out of jail early if you agreed
to do what they wanted you to do, like
maybe start a political podcast to push
their propaganda. First of all,
I don't push the CIA's propaganda. I am
the most famous and most vocal
critic of the CIA in America.
Number two, they didn't let me out of
prison early and it was prison, not
jail. It was the real deal.
They didn't let me out early. In fact,
I served every single day
of my sentence.
And it cost me my pension. It cost me my
marriage. It cost me my relationship
with my children.
It cost me literally everything. I had
to file for bankruptcy.
So, first of all, with all due respect,
buddy,
your question shows
it shows
incredible intellectual laziness.
Everybody can say, "Oh, once CIA, always
CIA." First of all, that is such
nonsense.
If you just add two and two, you come up
with four.
There's no deep operation to try to
trick Gavin into secretly believing CIA
propaganda. My God, man.
You want to see a CIA apologist? Go look
at Andrew Bustamante's podcast.
Or Shawn Ryan.
Not the foremost CIA critic in America.
Oh my God. Evan,
what do you think of the fraud
situations happening around the country?
For for instance, possible election
fraud in California and Somalian fraud
in Minnesota. Um apples and oranges, but
um there's always fraud in America.
Always. Always has been. From the
founding of the Republic.
Um I'm not seeing election fraud in
California. I see a lot of
allegations of election fraud in
California. I'm not seeing fraud. Last
year, seven people all across America
were convicted of
um election fraud.
And all seven
voted for Donald Trump.
So,
you know, stop watching Newsmax and OAN
and Fox.
There is no widespread election fraud.
Now, the fraud in Minnesota,
the Somali fraud, this is large-scale
fraud for which people need to go to
prison for a long time.
And
I hope that the authorities get to the
bottom of it because people people need
to be punished for that.
But election fraud?
Not out there.
Like I say, lots of allegations, but
anybody can make an allegation about
anything.
Proving it is an entirely different
issue.
Ivan
or Evan.
In a previous interview, you mentioned
that 99% of the tools used at the CIA
for spy work actually come from Amazon.
That is super interesting to me. Do you
happen to have any specific examples of
items you used
or a favorite story about how they
helped a mission? Yeah.
I was in Pakistan when the
pen recorder was invented.
And
dang, we used to take that thing into
every single meeting. Cuz it looks like
a pen and it's a little tiny camera.
Back then it didn't have much in the way
of memory.
But
we did it just to see if it would work
operationally.
And it always worked.
It was immensely helpful. There was
another thing we used in Athens, 1998,
1999, 2000. That's when the GPS was
invented. Not the GPS as we know it
today, where it just gives you a route
and you follow the route. The GPS back
then would just identify like, "Oh,
you're you're in view of like five
satellites now."
Or seven satellites, or two satellites.
And you click a button and it gives you
your geo coordinates.
So, we were able to use that in order to
to map out surveillance detection routes
that had been successful.
So, it helped us, you know, come up with
safer and different surveillance
detection routes.
But yeah, like I've said in the past,
it's a lot easier and it's way, way
cheaper
to just buy technologies that have
already been created than to create them
from scratch and spend, you know,
millions and millions of dollars doing
it.
Jacob,
"Hey John, love the show." Thank you,
Jacob. "But I have to admit I was blown
away when you said that Sharia law
wasn't
was nothing to worry about. When I look
at countries ruled by Islamic
leadership, they are all war-torn and
leaving Islam, apostasy, is a crime. Gay
people are thrown off buildings, little
girls are married off."
Um, not exactly true. Uh, gay people are
thrown off buildings by ISIS.
Not by any government.
Dude, if you go to Egypt, for example,
which is a Muslim country,
they've got very active, you know, LGBT
cultures.
Same thing in Jordan, same thing all
over the Persian Gulf.
Um, nobody's throwing anybody off
buildings except ISIS. And in that case,
they were throwing other Muslims off
buildings, not gays or lesbians or
whatever. Uh, little girls are married
off. Have you ever been to Mississippi
or Alabama
where it's legal to marry off a
14-year-old?
Come on, man.
Um, leaving Islam is a crime.
It is, and people leave Islam every
single day.
Uh, the only place where apostasy is
punished is Pakistan.
And that's way more cultural than it is
religious. But my original point, I
think, bears repeating. My original
point is that Sharia law is not
throwing people off buildings
or marrying off little girls. That's not
what Sharia law is. Sharia law is things
like um,
inheritance practices
or insurance or education
or property ownership or disputes
involving money between business
partners. That's what Sharia law is.
The the Quran lays out how disputes are
supposed to be
fixed.
That's Sharia law.
Not these acts of violence.
Stephen, how much of the skills you
learned in the field do you still use as
a civilian today, decades after federal
service? All of them.
My second book is called Doing Time Like
a Spy: How the CIA Taught Me to Survive
and Thrive in Prison.
And that book is about how I used those
skills in prison. Well, I've got another
book coming out uh, like it's it's
something like The Ultimate Guide to CIA
Tactics, Techniques, and Something. It's
coming out
uh,
August 11th.
Um, and it it shows how
you can use every one of those
techniques
um, in everyday life. Surveillance,
surveillance detection,
counter-surveillance, lying, lie
detection, and disappearing and living
off the grid. That's what the book uh,
covers.
Tiger, I know you love to travel. Yes, I
do. From your experiences, which country
would you say is the most beautiful has
the best food is the cheapest and is the
most easily navigable? What a wonderful
question that is. Okay, yes. First I'll
say my favorite country. I'm totally
biased, I admit, but my favorite country
is Greece.
I go to Greece two, three times a year.
I was there 2 weeks ago. I'm going again
in 2 weeks. I'm going again in November.
I was there in March, so four times this
year.
Um
Greece is my favorite.
And I believe Greece has the best food.
Hands down, no comparison.
I eat like a pig when I'm there, and
invariably I always always lose weight.
Okay.
The most beautiful
I'm going to give you two answers. In
terms of natural beauty, Oman, which is
on the southeastern tip of the Arabian
Peninsula. You've never seen landscape
like this before.
Thousand-foot cliffs going right to the
ocean. Incredible.
People They call them escarpments.
People
uh go camping in the desert, and they'll
just go to the top of the escarpment.
The view is unlike anything you've ever
seen before in your life.
So, in terms of natural beauty, Oman. In
terms of the beauty of the civilization
and the culture, it's got to be Syria.
You go to Damascus,
and you're looking at stuff that's
mentioned in the Bible, like by name.
Damascus Gate, and there are cars
driving through it.
It's mentioned in the Bible, for
heaven's sake. Oh, and there's this
little house over here. That's the house
where Saint Ananias lowered Saint Paul
in a basket so he could escape from the
Romans.
It's
just an incredible thing to see.
The cheapest
I'll tell you a funny story about Chile.
When I was in Chile, it was the cheapest
place I had ever been in my life. First
of all, it is an absolutely wonderful
country. Beautiful,
friendly people, plenty to do.
Uh it's it's just an incredible place.
It's hard to get to,
but it's an incredible place.
So,
I went on my honeymoon, and my wife and
I went to this Chilean uh vineyard.
And we're doing, you know, wine tasting,
and oh, how nice is this, and oh, the
bouquet of that, and oh, you know, blah
blah blah.
Mostly taste the same to me, but anyway,
I said to the guy, just for fun, I said,
"What's like What's your most expensive,
most wonderful, most incredible wine
that you have?" "Oh," he goes,
"that's the director's special private
reserve vintage, you know, 2001,
blah blah blah." And I go I go,
"Can I taste it?"
And he says, "Well, it's
it's expensive, and it's locked up." I
said, "Ah, we're on our honeymoon. Let's
break open a bottle."
He gets this big ring of keys out. He
keys into this locked room. He comes out
with this bottle.
And he opens it up, and he pours two
glasses. There are the four glasses to a
bottle.
And we drink it, and it's magnificent.
And so, I said to him, "How much is it?"
And he takes a calculator, and he goes,
he goes, "$8.50."
And I said, "Oh my god." I go,
"You guys have a really nice country
here.
You need to raise your prices."
So, I bought a case and shipped it back.
The shipping cost more than the wine
did.
I shipped it back to the United States.
One of the best wines I ever had in my
life, Concha y Toro.
Um but there are a lot of great places
out there. And you know, here I am after
all these years, and I'm still
discovering new places. Like I just went
to Norway and Sweden 2 weeks ago for the
very first time in my life. How I missed
Sweden,
which was an awesome, gorgeous place
with wonderful people and great food and
amazing nightlife and coffee culture and
great bars. I don't know how I missed
it. Next week, I'm going to Vietnam.
I've never been to Vietnam, looking
forward to it. I'll do the show from
Vietnam. So, I'm still out there
exploring the world. There are a lot of
places to see.
Uh Lester, how can we safeguard national
security and prevent the next 9/11 and
have accountability?
Dude,
that's really the $64,000 question.
You know, my official position is that
since the CIA was founded in 1947,
it has missed every major world event.
Every last one of them.
From, you know,
the establishment of the Berlin Wall
to the collapse of the Berlin Wall
to the collapse of the Soviet Union
uh the Iran hostage crisis
9/11. I mean, you name it, they got it
wrong.
So, spending more money, throwing money
at the CIA and NSA and DOD, that's not
the answer.
To prevent the next 9/11,
maybe we shouldn't have,
you know, 200 bases in 144 countries
pissing people off and trampling on
their civil rights and their civil
liberties.
Maybe we shouldn't get in bed with the
Israelis and just allow them to commit
genocide against
innocent Palestinian civilians.
Maybe if we weren't around the world
pissing people off so badly, we wouldn't
have to worry about the next 9/11.
Accountability is another issue.
Um
we have a cowardly political system in
this country
where there is no accountability.
Like did literally anybody lose their
job even
for 9/11?
Of course not. They all got promoted.
They all got rich. They all went on to
the boards of directors of, you know,
intelligence community contractors and
defense contractors. Everybody got rich.
Everybody in Congress
that was asleep at the switch got
reelected.
So there's no accountability. We need we
need to start back from scratch again.
Nick, you mentioned meeting Donald Trump
in your most recent podcast episode.
When did you meet him and why? Did he
know who you were?
Funny story. Thank you for asking that.
I have a very wealthy friend. He's very
wealthy and very generous.
He also has a felony conviction in his
past. It's a conviction for
violating bank secrecy laws.
So stupid. But anyway, he called me one
day. We're very close. And he said,
"Buddy,
we got to get ourselves pardons." This
is a year and a half ago.
He said,
"What are you doing this weekend?" I
said, "Nothing." He says, "I'm going to
fly you to Mar-a-Lago. I'm going to meet
you in Mar-a-Lago. We're going to have
lunch. And if the president's there,
we're just going to pitch him and ask
him to pardon us." And I said, "Hey,
let's do it." So he flies me down to the
Palm Beach
and um
and we go to Mar-a-Lago. It is very very
difficult to get in. There are four
layers of security. This is right after
um the second attempt on uh
on President Trump. And so
with we finally get to the to the desk.
We had made reservations. And the lady
at the desk cleared our names. And she
said, "Have you been here before?" We
said, "No."
She said, "There are three rules.
No photos. No videos.
No hats in the dining room, including
Make America Great Again hats.
And don't ever approach the president.
If he wants to talk, he'll approach you.
We said, "Fine." We go in, he's not
there. I will say that it was the best
egg salad I'd ever had in my entire
life.
So, just as we're finishing lunch, he
walks in with Mark Zuckerberg, no less.
And everybody politely
you know, politely
collapse like that, and then he, you
know,
waves, and then he sits down in the
corner over here with Zuckerberg. And
they're talking, whispering to each
other. They finish lunch,
and Zuckerberg gets up and leaves. They
shake hands, and he just walks out.
And everybody's kind of like, you know,
looking like this, like the side eye
look, "What's he going to do? What's he
going to do?"
And he gets up, and he goes to the first
table. It's a bunch of blondes
with
big boobs, probably all auditioning for
Fox News. So,
I said to my buddy, "Oh my god, he's
com- he's going to come over here."
So, he goes from table to table, and I'm
ready. I'm ready for him. So, he comes
over, and I stand up, and I I
went to my go-to line. I said, "Mr.
President,
I'm John Kiriakou, the CIA torture
whistleblower.
Barack Obama and John Brennan ruined my
life, and you are the only person who
can give it back to me."
And he goes like this.
"Tucker told me about you." And I said,
"Yes, sir. Tucker's been a great
supporter of mine." And he says, "And
Dershowitz?" And I said, "Yes, sir. Uh
Professor Dershowitz wrote a letter to
you, um asking that you pardon me."
And he said, "Right. Well,
talk to Pam Bondi."
And I said, "Okay, I'll do that." And he
says, "Pam Bondi will get the get the
process going." I said, "Thank you, Mr.
President." And then my buddy gives his
pitch, and then Trump goes to the next
table. Okay, we leave.
That afternoon, later that afternoon, uh
I went over to the apartment of um
of a very prominent
former Democrat, now Republican
campaign
big shot.
A a household name.
And he said, "Well, how did it go?" I
said, "It went great." And I I told him
what had happened.
And while I'm telling the story, he
picks up his phone and he starts dialing
a number and I I think to myself,
"That's kind of rude, just dialing a
number like that."
And then
he puts it on speaker and the guy says,
"Hey, you know, I'm going to make up a
name. Jimmy baby, how you doing, buddy?"
And it's Trump.
And he says, "Mr. President, I'm sitting
here with the two gentlemen that you met
earlier today, John Kiriakou and my
friend.
And um
just wanted to tell you these are these
are good men and they deserve a pardon."
He said, "Yeah, I I talked to them." He
said, "I told them to talk to Pam
Bondi." He said, "Okay, Mr. President, I
just want you to know that they've got
my support. I think they're they're
deserving of pardons." And he said,
"Okay, they know what to do." And we
hung up.
I said, "Man, I didn't know you were
that connected. I mean, I knew you were
connected, but not that connected." Then
he says,
"Now is the
awkward moment when I ask you for
$25,000."
And I said, "Come on, man. I don't have
$25, let alone $25,000."
Let alone $25,000.
And he says, "A month
until you get the pardon."
And I said, "No can do."
So, I decided, you know, Tucker fell out
of favor, of course, so I decided
after this first letter went to the
president, um Pam Bondi did literally
nothing from for me and it turns out her
brother was selling pardons and it was a
big deal.
Um
but I have a second letter now signed by
household names
in American politics. And uh
hoping for the best. I will say that
Donald Trump in person in that short
exchange was nothing like Donald Trump
on television.
He was warm and engaging and friendly
and
I wonder how much of the tough guy
Donald Trump is is an act for political
purposes.
I don't know. I don't know him well
enough. I only met him for
60 seconds.
Sam says, "Across your whole career, is
there any piece that you regret? Would
you do it again?" I regret a lot.
Yeah, there's a lot that I regret.
A lot.
Like way too much to go into here.
Um but you know what though, I wonder
Sam if that just comes with um
being an adult and advancing age. We all
look back on our lives and when we
ponder the mistakes that we made. I'm
married twice and I'm divorced twice.
And uh
you know, while I've been transparent
about why I got divorced.
Um
I I'm I would never say that I was an
innocent in all of this. First of all,
I've never cheated. I would never cheat.
I will never cheat. I have nothing but
utter contempt and disgust and revulsion
for cheaters.
Especially at the CIA. If your own
spouse can't trust you, how is the
country supposed to trust you?
You know?
But with that said, I focused way too
much on the job.
And then when I blew the whistle and got
bogged down in my own bull
um
yeah, I wasn't paying attention to the
people around me.
So there's a there's a lot I regret.
Well, folks, anyway, that's all the time
we have for today. And I want to thank
you again for sending in the questions.
Please keep sending them.
jkbradmin@gmail.com
and uh we're we'll do our very best to
uh to get to your question. Please,
again, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the YouTube channel. Please
follow me on Instagram, TikTok. All the
links are in the descrip the
description. I'm on Cameo, which has
been a ton of fun. So, check things out
on Cameo and my other podcast, which is
called John Kiriakou's Dead Drop. It is
on Apple Podcasts and Spotify. Thank you
again and we'll see you next time.